Papers of Morris K. Udall, 1920-1995
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
- Legislative Files, 1961-1990
  - Staff Project Files, 1963-1990
    - Central Arizona Project, 1963-1985
      - Tucson Aqueduct-Correspondence. 1982 (Box 487, Folder 11)
      - Tucson Aqueduct-General. 1982 (Box 487, Folder 12-13)
      - Tucson Aqueduct-Phase B, Supplemental Reporting Data. 1983 (Box 487, Folder 14)
      - Tucson Aqueduct-Udall Memos. 1981-1982 (Box 487, Folder 15)
      - Orme Dam-Robos. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 16)
      - Orme Dam-James Watt News Release. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 17)
      - Orme Dam-James Watt Correspondence. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 18-19)
      - Orme Dam-James Watt Meeting. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 20)
      - Orme Dam-Charts, Capacities. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 21)
      - Orme Dam-Controversy Amongst Arizona Congressional Delegation. 1981 (Box 487, Folder 22)
      - Orme Dam-Udall Memos, Press Releases. 1981-1983 (Box 487, Folder 23)
      - Udall Notebooks. 1977 (Box 488, Folder 1)
      - Udall Notebooks-Presentation to Arizona Congressional Delegation. 1977 (Box 488, Folder 2)
      - Udall Notebooks. 1979 (Box 488, Folder 3)
      - Udall Notebooks, #1. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 4)
      - Udall Notebooks, #2. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 5)
      - Udall Notebooks, #3. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 6)
      - Udall Notebooks-McNulty Files. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 7)
      - Udall Notebooks-Water and Power Resources. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 8)
      - Udall Notebooks-Congressional Briefing. 1980 (Box 488, Folder 9)
      - Udall Notebooks-Central Arizona Project Status. 1981 (Box 488, Folder 10-11)
      - Udall Notebooks-Central Arizona Project Status. 1983 (Box 488, Folder 12)
      - Udall Notebooks. 1981 (Box 488, Folder 13)
      - Udall Notebooks. 1983 (Box 488, Folder 14-15)
      - Reports: Final Environmental Statement. 1972 (Box 489, Folder 1)
      - Reports: Final Environmental Statement-Salt-Gila Aqueduct Eastern Pima County Regional Water Resources Study; Sizing of the Salt-Gila Aqueduct/Craig Phillips. 1979 (Box 489, Folder 2)
      - Reports: Public Workshops-Central Arizona Water Control Study. 1980 (Box 489, Folder 3)
      - Reports. 1981 (Box 489, Folder 4)
        Tucson Aqueduct-Phase B, Stage I Work Plan
        Safety of Dams Salt River Project Evaluation
        Water Allocations and Water Service Contracting
        Tucson Aqueduct Phase A, Stage II Report; Central Arizona Water Control Study
        Summary Factbook
        Central Arizona Water Control Study
      - Reports: Tucson Aqueduct, Phase B, Plan Formulation Working Document; EIS Tucson Aqueduct Phase A. 1982 (Box 489, Folder 5)
      - Reports: Briefing on CAP to the Central Arizona Water Conservation District; Environmental Impact Statement, Regulatory Storage Division. 1983 (Box 489, Folder 6)
      - Reports: EIS, Regulatory Storage Division CAP (2 Vols); Probable Maximum Floor, Salt and Verde River Basins. 1983 (Box 490, Folder 1)
      - Reports: CAP Status; Stage II, Report Addendum. 1984 (Box 490, Folder 2)
      - Reports. 1985 (Box 490, Folder 3)
        Draft and Final of EIS Tucson Aqueduct, Phase B
        Final EIS New Waddell Dam Design Modifications, Maricopa County, AZ
        Gila River and Tributaries, Rillito River and Associated Streams
        Master Plan and 10 Year Capital Improvement Program
      - Reports: Pinal Active Management Area Technical Report, Cooperative Agricultural Study, Pinal Active Management Area. 1986 (Box 490, Folder 4)
      - Reports: Tohono O'odham Nation, Water Resource Program Master Plan; Field Implementation for the La Quituni Study Basin; Resolution of the Tohono O'Odham Legislative Council. 1987 (Box 490, Folder 5)
      - Reports: Environmental Assessment of the Schuk Toak Development Plan, Tohono O'Odham Nation. 1988 (Box 490, Folder 6)
      - Reports: Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act Substantiating Report, CAP, Verde and East Verde River Water Diversions, Yavapai and Gila Counties. 1989 (Box 490, Folder 7)
      - Reports. 1990 (Box 490, Folder 8)
        Environmental Assessment Safety of Dams Modification, Verde River, Salt River Project
        Environmental Assessment Proposed Safety of Dams Modifications to Horseshoe and Bartlett Dams on the Verde River
        Loan Application Report for the Schuck Toak District, Tohono O'Odham Nation
      - Bills and Hearings. 1951-1952, 1963-1968 (Box 491, Folder 1)
        Includes seven bound volumes:
        82nd Congress 1951-1952 (2)
        88th Congress, 1963-1964 (2)
        89th Congress, 1965-1966
        90th Congress, 1967-1968
      - Interior Committee: Bureau of Reclamation. 1981-1982 (Box 492, Folder 1)
      - Interior Committee: Colorado River Projects, Budgets. 1983-1990 (Box 492, Folder 2)
      - Interior Committee: Clippings. 1985-1987 (Box 492, Folder 3-4)
      - Interior Committee: Correspondence. No Date (Box 492, Folder 5)
      - Interior Committee: Colorado River Basin Project, Data Sheets. 1985-1986 (Box 492, Folder 6)
      - Interior Committee: Colorado River Basin Project, Reports. 1979-1980 (Box 492, Folder 7)
      - Interior Committee: Correspondence to Arizona Water Community. 1983-1986 (Box 492, Folder 8)
      - Interior Committee: Distribution Systems. 1981-1982 (Box 492, Folder 9)
      - Interior Committee: General Reference Materials. 1980-1989 (Box 492, Folder 10)
      - Interior Committee: General Reference Material. 1980-1989 (Box 493, Folder 1)
      - Interior Committee: Press Releases. 1987-1988 (Box 493, Folder 2)
      - Interior Committee: Udall Notebooks. 1979-1980 (Box 493, Folder 3)
      - Interior Committee: Udall Notebooks. 1983-1984 (Box 493, Folder 4-7)
      - Interior Committee: "Watergram" Issue. 1985-1989 (Box 493, Folder 8)
      - Interior Committee: Plan 6 Funding. 1985 (Box 493, Folder 9)
    - Public Land Law Review Commission (PLLRC), 1964-1970
      On October 15, 1962, the 87th Congress House Interior and Insular Affairs Committee Chairman Wayne N. Aspinall (D-Colorado) wrote to President John F. Kennedy suggesting the need for a broader examination of public land policy and inviting submission of the President's views to the 88th Congress. The President concurred and instructed the Secretaries of the Interior (Stewart Udall) and Agriculture (Orville Freeman) to represent him. On August 14, 1963, Chairman Aspinall introduced a bill to establish the Public Land Law Review Commission and on September 19, 1964, President Johnson signed Public Law 88-606 establishing the PLLRC with 19 members. The commission was charged to make a comprehensive review of the public land laws and the rules, regulations, policies and practices of Federal, state and local governments and agencies; recommend any necessary modifications and prepare a final report.
      Congressman Aspinall was named Chairman, six members were appointed by the President, six by the U.S. Senate and six by the U.S. House. The Senate and House members changed from time to time, because of election defeats and resignations. Thirty-four individuals were selected by the Commission and Federal agencies to serve as an Advisory Council. The commission was authorized to hire fifty-four staff members and Milton Pearl served as the Director from 1964-1970. Congressman Morris K. Udall served on the Commission from 1967 to 1970, when the final report was issued and the commission disbanded.
      Arranged chronologically within six broad series: the correspondence of Congressman Udall related to the commission; the PLLRC operational materials including background, history, correspondence, memos, press releases, personnel, procedures and public meetings, budget, transcripts, clippings, final reports, conferences and speeches; Chairman Aspinall's papers including correspondence, reference materials, clippings, and speeches; the subject study areas of the PLLRC; Director Milton Pearl's files and copies of reports which are also arranged by the same subject study areas. The subject study area files include draft and final reports, correspondence with contractors performing the studies and reviews of the reports. The subject study areas include:
      Acquisitions and Exchanges
      Adjustments of Use Rights
      Administrative Procedures
      Alaska
      Appraisal Techniques
      Criteria
      Demand
      Disposal of Public Lands
      Economic Impacts
      Energy and Nonfuel Minerals
      Environment
      Fish and Wildlife
      Forage
      Independent Recovery and Coordinating Agency
      Intensive Agriculture
      Inventory
      Land Disposal Techniques
      Land Grants to States
      Legislative Jurisdiction
      Organization, Administration and Budgeting
      Outdoor Recreation
      Outer Continental Shelf
      Public Land - New Cities Acquisition and Exchange
      Recreation
      Regional and Local Uses
      Revenue Sharing
      State Land Policy Inventory
      Timber Trespass
      Use and Occupancy
      User Fees and Charges
      Water
      Withdrawals
      Contains correspondence, telegrams, memos, press releases, annotated drafts of subject study area reports and final reports, reviews of reports, maps, clippings and speeches. The bulk of these files relate to the subject study areas listed above. Deaccessioned from these series were duplicate copies of reports, correspondence, clippings, reference materials, government publications, memos, and routine commission administrative files including receipts for supplies, telephone, stamps, job requests, contractors expense vouchers, requests for publications and mass mailing postcards.
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Udall Correspondence. 1969-1970 (Box 494, Folder 1-2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Background Materials. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 3-5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Clippings. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 6-7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, History. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, General and Correspondence. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Reports and Study Plans. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 10)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records- Objectives, Functions, Operations. 1966 (Box 494, Folder 11)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Procedures Notebook. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 12)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Public Meetings. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 13-14)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Correspondence. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 15)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Press Releases. 1964-1967 (Box 494, Folder 16)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Press Releases. 1967-1970 (Box 494, Folder 17)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Personnel. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 18)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Members. 1964-1970 (Box 494, Folder 19)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Operational Records, Digest of Public Land Laws. No Date (Box 494, Folder 20)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, White House Comments on PLLRC. 1964-1970 (Box 495, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Staff Memos. 1965-1967 (Box 495, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Staff Memos. 1968-1970 (Box 495, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Budget. 1971 (Box 495, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Milton A. Pearl-Advisory Council Members Statements. No Date (Box 495, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Transcripts. 1966 (Box 495, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Final Report. No Date (Box 495, Folder 7-12)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Denver. September 1970 (Box 495, Folder 13)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, II Proceedings-Interim Committee Concerned with Activities of PLLRC. October 1969 (Box 495, Folder 14)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Western States Land Commissioners. September 1970 (Box 495, Folder 15)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Battelle Seattle Research Center. September 1970 (Box 495, Folder 16)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences-Trail Lake, Wyoming. September 1970 (Box 495, Folder 17)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences-Portland, Oregon. October 1970 (Box 495, Folder 18-19)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences-Boise, Idaho. November 1970 (Box 495, Folder 20)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences-Denver, Colorado. November 1970 (Box 495, Folder 21)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Speeches-General. (Box 495, Folder 22-23)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Staff Conferences, Speeches-Chairman Aspinall, Director Pearl. (Box 495, Folder 24)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Papers, Correspondence. (Box 495, Folder 25)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Papers, Reference Material. (Box 495, Folder 26)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Papers, Personal Clippings. (Box 495, Folder 27)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Aspinall Papers, Speeches. (Box 495, Folder 28-29)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Administrative Procedures. (Box 496, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Alaska. (Box 496, Folder 2-4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Map Supplements to Part III, Section A of Public Land Policy and the Environment. (Box 496, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Appraisal Techniques and Procedures. (Box 496, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Discussion Papers of Guidelines for Retention or Disposition of the Public Lands. 1970 (Box 496, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Budget. (Box 496, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Contracts. (Box 496, Folder 9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Criteria Study Plan. (Box 496, Folder 10)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Demand Study. (Box 496, Folder 11)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Economic Impact Study. (Box 496, Folder 12)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Energy Fuels. (Box 497, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Coal. (Box 497, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Competitive Oil and Gas Leasing. (Box 497, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Oil Shale. (Box 497, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Environment and Ecological Factors. (Box 497, Folder 5-6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Exchanges and Acquisitions. (Box 497, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Federal Jurisdiction. (Box 498, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Fish and Wildlife. (Box 498, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Forage. (Box 498, Folder 3-4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Intensive Agriculture. (Box 498, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Inventory of Public Lands and Resources. (Box 498, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Issues. (Box 498, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Land Disposal Techniques & Procedures Study. (Box 498, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Land Grants to States. (Box 498, Folder 9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Legislation Commission. (Box 498, Folder 10)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Multiple Use. (Box 498, Folder 11)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Nonfuel Minerals. (Box 499, Folder 1-2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Oregon and California Grant Lands. (Box 499, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Organization-Administrative and Budgetary Policy. (Box 499, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Outer Continental Shelf. (Box 499, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Outdoor Recreation. (Box 499, Folder 6-7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Regional and Local Land Use Planning. (Box 499, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Revenue Sharing. (Box 500, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, State Land Policies. (Box 500, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Timber. (Box 500, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy. (Box 500, Folder 4-6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy-Letters Opposing HR 7211 and Favoring HR 9911. (Box 501, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy-Clippings, BLM and Land Use. (Box 501, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy-American Mining Congress. (Box 501, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy-Paper, Public Land Policy and the Environment. (Box 501, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Use and Occupancy-Interstate Association of Public Land Counties. (Box 501, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, User Fees and Charges. (Box 501, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Trespass. (Box 501, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Water. (Box 501, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Subject Study Areas, Withdrawals and Reservations. (Box 501, Folder 9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Acquisitions and Exchanges. (Box 502, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Adjustments of Use Rights. (Box 502, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Administrative Procedures. (Box 502, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Alaska. (Box 502, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Appraisal Techniques. (Box 502, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Disposal of Public Lands. (Box 502, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Economic Impacts. (Box 502, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Energy and Nonfuel Minerals. (Box 502, Folder 8-9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Environment. (Box 502, Folder 10)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Fish and Wildlife. (Box 503, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Forage. (Box 503, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Independent Recovery and Coordinating Agency. (Box 503, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Intensive Agriculture. (Box 503, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Inventory. (Box 503, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Land Disposal Techniques. (Box 503, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Land Grants to States. (Box 503, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Legislative Jurisdiction. (Box 503, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files-Organization, Administration and Budgeting. (Box 503, Folder 9)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Outdoor Recreation. (Box 503, Folder 10)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Outer Continental Shelf. (Box 504, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Public Lands-New Cities Acquisition and Exchange. (Box 504, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Recreation. (Box 504, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Regional and Local Use. (Box 504, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Revenue Sharing. (Box 504, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, State Land Policies Inventory. (Box 504, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Timber. (Box 504, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Trespass. (Box 504, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Use and Occupancy. (Box 505, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, User Fees and Charges. (Box 505, Folder 2)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Water. (Box 505, Folder 3)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Withdrawals and Reservations. (Box 505, Folder 4)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Draft Final Report. (Box 505, Folder 5)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Final Report-"One Third of A Nation." (Box 505, Folder 6)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Director Pearl's Files, Subject Study Area Reports (Unbound Volumes). (Box 505, Folder 7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Public Lands/McFarland, Carl. (Box 506, Folder 1)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures- Federal Land Laws and Policies in Alaska, Vols.1-5/Harkin, Duncan A. (Box 506, Folder 2-7)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Criteria for Public Land Decision/Hagenstein, Perry. (Box 506, Folder 8)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Energy Fuel Mineral Resources of the Public Lands Vols.1-5/ABT Associates, Inc. (Box 506, Folder 9-13)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Federal Legislative Jurisdiction/Commission Staff. (Box 506, Folder 14)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Fish and Wildlife Resources on Public Lands/Colorado State University. (Box 506, Folder 15-16)
      - Public Land Law Review Commission: Bound Volumes, Administrative Procedures-Future Demands on the Public Lands/Bennett, et al. (Box 506, Folder 17-20)